[Music]
hi welcome back to the channel today's
video is another top ben and jerry's one
this is part of their new range we did
the thick mint i'll put a link down
below for that one this is their
tiramisu topped which is a mascarpone
ice cream with fudge swirl shortbread
pieces espresso fudge topped with
a ganache topping too so it all sounds
really good if you want to see how we
make it stick around and we'll show you
we're going to start with the ice cream
base so for this let's add our 500
milliliters of milk to a pan and add in
our 120 grams of sugar which has already
got the stabilizer in it
also add your 40 grams of dextrose and
40 grams of corn syrup you can use
golden syrup if you're in the uk or
anywhere else it doesn't have corn syrup
start heating it up and add in the 15
grams of skim milk powder and 10 grams
of butter finally add in the silk gel
this is an emulsifier to blend the
ingredients and the butter in properly
if you don't have silk joe you can use
another emulsifier
finally add in half of your mascarpone
so 200 grams and stir that in well turn
off the heat and then add the final 200
grams of cold mascarpone transfer that
to a container and store it in the
fridge overnight
[Music]
for the fudge swell simply add all your
ingredients to a pan and heat it well
while stirring get it to a rolling boil
and let it bubble away for at least one
minute transfer that into a container
and you can store that in the fridge for
now
[Music]
so the espresso fudge is a nice simple
recipe too add in 400 grams of condensed
milk and 340 grams of 50 chocolate to a
pan heat that up until the chocolate is
all melted and it's all lovely and
combined finally add in two tablespoons
of instant espresso powder and stir that
in well turn off the heat and then press
it down into a lined 8x8 baking pan
cool that down to room temperature and
store it in the freezer overnight
[Music]
when the base is chilled get it churning
in your machine
whilst that's happening take some of
your espresso fudge and chop it into
small pieces and keep it in a tub at the
side ready
also chop up your shortbread we've used
shop bought shortbread here but we'll
put a recipe down below should you want
to try and make it yourself
finally melt 50 grams of 50 chocolate
with one teaspoon of coconut oil as this
is going to be your ganache top
[Music]
when your ice cream is ready start
loading up by layering the shortbread
fudge swirl and ice cream and for the
top place the espresso fudge onto the
ice cream itself and pour over your
chocolate ganache
store the result in the freezer for at
least four hours
[Music]
so
now we had a discussion about the tub
design for this neither of us could
think of anything vaguely related to
tiramisu so
we took the one main ingredient which
was mascarpone
and
there we have
the tub i love this one it's great
let's just smash that ganache top and
get some dished out into the bowl shall
we
[Music]
and there we go
i mean look at that fudge just really
good fudge it's a little bit thinner
than other fudge swells that i make so
it stays quite liquid when it's in your
ice cream which is really handy when you
scoop and it's all still gooey and drips
out it's really nice
let's just dig in and try this i'm
really excited i haven't tried this one
yet so let's see what it tastes like
[Music]
this is really good this is really
really good the ice cream itself now
i've obviously had tiramisu before if
you don't know what tiramisu is it's an
italian dessert that
has espresso laced
sponge fingers or ladyfingers as they're
called over here with a mascarpone cream
with cocoa powders and
it's a really
luxurious dessert
i didn't know how it would work in ice
cream form it's not a flavor i can buy
in the shops over here
but the cream cheese which jenny's uses
cream cheese and her recipe books but
not like this she just has a little bit
added into it but this whole mask pony
based ice cream is incredibly luxurious
silky smooth mouth feel that there's
zero iciness in this ice cream at all
combine that with that
just strong enough chocolate fudge the
crunch of the shortbread biscuit in
there is really nice
the ganache top is perfect this time so
i didn't screw this one up like i did
last time
now the espresso it just comes in you
need that chocolate now what i guess
what they i wish they would have done is
add a little bit more coffee element to
it so maybe if you made an espresso
fudge swirl that would have helped bring
a little bit more coffee flavor into it
i don't know why they missed out a trick
on adding
more caffeine in their ice cream but
either way this is an excellent ice
cream and i can see why it's really well
reviewed on their website so i hope
you've enjoyed the making of this one
and do give this one a try i don't know
if you can get much money where you are
if not
i'm sure any other cream cheese will
work
give it a try let me know how it goes
thanks very much for watching don't
forget to like and subscribe and we'll
see you next week
[Music]